Fred Snitzer collection of Kings County Postal ephemera 2013.003
Brooklyn Historical Society
Fred Snitzer collection of Kings County postal ephemera
1717-2010
1850-1950
Center for Brooklyn History
Brooklyn Daily Eagle (Firm)
Snitzer, Fred
Lacks, Monica
Skurnick, Randy
2013.003
22 Linear Feet in 36 manuscript boxes, 4 oversized manuscript boxes, and 1 record carton
The collection primarily consists of Kings County postcards and envelopes (covers) collected by Fred Snitzer, the bulk of which date from 1850 to 1950. It also includes letters (housed with related envelopes), clippings, invoices, property records, and Brooklyn history and postal collecting reference materials.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Arrangement
The collection's organization is based on Snitzer's system of arrangement. Folder titles are derived from Snitzer's original labels. Any folder titles supplied by the processing archivist have been enclosed in brackets.
The collection is organized into four series:
Series 1: Postcards
Series 2: Covers
Series 3: Memorabilia
Series 4: Reference
Related Materials
The Martin L. Severe collection of first day covers (2014.013) also contains Kings County related covers.
The New York Public Library Archives and Manuscripts Division holds the Fred Snitzer chess collection, 1910-1951 (MssCol 2802).
Separated Materials
Twelve books relating to Brooklyn history have been removed to the library's book collection. These include the following:
Ierardi, Eric J. Gravesend: The home of Coney Island
Israelowitz, Oscar. Borough Park: Centennial Edition 1898-1998
Israelowitz, Oscar. Oscar Israelowitz's Flatbush guide
Jackson and Manbeck. The neighborhoods of Brooklyn
Lancaster, Clay. Old Brooklyn Heights: New York's first suburb
Landesman, Alter F. A History of New Lots, Brooklyn - to 1887
Merlis, Brian. Brooklyn: The Centennial Edition
Merlis, Brian. Brooklyn: The way it was
Merlis, Brian, et al. Brooklyn's Gold Coast
Merlis, Brian. Welcome back to Brooklyn
Robbins and Palitz. Brooklyn: a state of mind
Snow, Richard. Coney Island: A postcard journey to the city of fire
Additionally, photocopies of the Brooklyn Eagle's guides to Brooklyn, Bushwick, Flatbush, Flatlands, Gravesend, and New Utrecht have been discarded. Originals are available in the library.
Biographical note
Fred Snitzer was born in 1929. He was a longtime resident of Brooklyn and attended New Utrecht High School. He later resided at 75 Henry Street in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. He was self employed as an investment counselor, an expert rated chess player, a world traveler, and a collector of Brooklyn postal ephemera. He died, in Brooklyn, on October 26, 2012.
Sources
"Fred Snitzer (1929-2012)" by Phillip R. Smith. The United States Chess Federation website. Accessed January 28, 2015. http://www.uschess.org/content/view/11981/512/
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated by Monica Lacks and Randy Skurnick, as representatives of the Estate of Fred Snitzer, in 2013.
Scope and Contents
The collection primarily consists of Kings County postcards and envelopes (covers) collected by Fred Snitzer, the bulk of which date from 1850 to 1950. It also includes letters (housed with related envelopes), clippings, invoices, property records, ephemera, and Brooklyn history and postal collecting reference materials. Snitzer's extensive collection includes cross-references (photocopies) between the various series and sub-series of postal ephemera.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The majority of the materials in this collection are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org at least three weeks prior to research visit.
Envelopes; Postcards; Picture postcards; Postage stamps; Postal service |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Stamp collecting |z New York (State) |z Kings County; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1914-1918; Deeds; Newsletters; Correspondence; Transportation |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); Navy-yards and naval stations |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Amusement parks |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brooklyn Bridge (New York, N.Y.); Books; Long Island, Battle of, New York, N.Y., 1776; United States |x History |y Civil War, 1861-1865; Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Catalogs; Coney Island (New York, N.Y.); Prospect Park (New York, N.Y.); Flatbush (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Floyd Bennett Field (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn Daily Eagle (Firm); New York Naval Shipyard; Long Island Postal History Society; United States Postal Service; Delapierre family; Lacks, Monica; Van Brunt family; Skurnick, Randy; Snitzer, Fred
- Series 1: Postcards, 1873-2009; 1900-1940; 6.5 Linear Feet in 13 manuscript boxes
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains 13 manuscript boxes of Kings County postcards and related clippings, dating from 1873 to 2009.
  The series is divided into 3 sub-series:
  Sub-series 1: Picture Postcards
  Sub-series 2: Chronological Postcards
  Sub-series 3: Brooklyn Eagle Postcards
  - Sub-series 1: Picture Postcards, 1874-2009; 1900-1930
    This subseries contains Kings County picture postcards, dating from 1874 to 2009.
    The sub-series is divided into five sections:
    1. Communities (Brooklyn neighborhoods)
    2. Bridges
    3. Coney Island
    4. Prospect Park and other parks
    5. Other topics (A-Z)
    Each section is arranged alphabetically. Please note that the labels which appear throughout this sub-series do not relate to the postcards currently housed in those sleeves. They were most likely rearranged by Snitzer at some point prior to donation.
    - Indexes, circa 2000s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1. Introduction; Communities: Bath Beach, Bensonhurst, 1890s-1920s; 2000s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 2. Communities: Bay Ridge, Bensonhurst, 1890s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 3. Communities: Bergen Beach, Borough Hall, 1890s-1920s; 2000s (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 4. Communities: Borough Hall, 1890s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 5. Communities: Borough Hall, Borough Park, Brighton Beach, 1890s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 6. Communities: Brighton Beach, Brooklyn Heights, 1890s-1920s; 1969-2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      General
      Map of Brooklyn Heights (1969)
    - 7. Communities: Bushwick, Clinton Hill, East New York, 1890s-1920s; 2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      See files 17-25 for Coney Island
    - 8. Communities: East New York, Flatbush, 1890s-1920s; 2001 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 9. Communities: Flatbush, 1890s-1920s (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 10. Communities: Flatbush, Fort Hamilton, 1890s-1920s (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 11. Communities: Fort Hamilton, Gravesend, Greenpoint, Homecrest, New Utrecht, Parkville, Prospect Park West/Park Slope, Ridgewood, 1890s-1920s; 2000s (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 12. Communities: Seagate, Sheepshead Bay, Williamsburg; Bridges: Brooklyn Bridge, 1890s-1920s; 2000s (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Coney Island Jockey Club badge
    - 13. Bridges: Brooklyn Bridge, 1890s-1920s; 2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 14. Bridges: Brooklyn Bridge, 1890s-1920s (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 15. Bridges: Brooklyn Bridge, 1890s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 16. Bridges: Brooklyn Bridge, Manhattan Bridge, Verrazano Bridge, Williamsburg Bridge, 1900s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 17. Bridges: Williamsburg Bridge, Miscellaneous; Coney Island: Introduction, 1900s-1920s; 1990s-2000s (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 18. Coney Island: Beach and Boardwalk, 1900s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 19. Coney Island: Beach and Boardwalk, Dreamland, 1900s (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 20. Coney Island: Dreamland, 1900s (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 21. Coney Island: Luna Park, 1900s-1910s; 2001 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 22. Coney Island: Luna Park, 1900s-1910s (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 23. Coney Island: Luna Park, Steeplechase, 1900s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 24. Coney Island: Street scenes, Individual amusements, 1900s-1950s; 2000s (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 25. Coney Island: Individual amusements, miscellaneous; Prospect Park: Entrances, 1900s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 26. Prospect Park: Entrances, 1900s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 27. Prospect Park: Entrances, the Lake, 1900s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 28. Prospect Park: The Lake, Bridges, 1900s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 29. Prospect Park: Bridges, Paths/Roadways, 1900s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 30. Prospect Park: Great Lawn, Flower Garden/Vale of Cashmere, Statues and monuments, 1900s-1910s (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 31. Prospect Park: Statues and monuments, Cafes and restaurants, Parade Grounds, Zoo, 1900s-1960s; 2000s (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 32. Prospect Park: Litchfield Mansion; Botanic Gardens; Parks, 1900s-1950s; 2000s (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 33. Parks, 1900s-1930s (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 34. Armories, 1900s-1910s (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 35. Banks, 1887-1930s (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 36 - 39. Churches (4 folders), 1900s-1950s; 2001 (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
    - 40. Private clubs and organizations, 1900s-1910s (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - 41. Private clubs and organizations; Schools: Public schools, 1894-1910s (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 42 - 45. Schools (4 folders), 1896-1950s; 1990s (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
    - 46. Fire, Police, and Utilities; Forts and Airfields, 1900s-1910s (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 47. Forts and Airfields; Historic and Landmark buildings, 1900s-1960s; 2000s (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - 48. Historic and Landmark buildings; Hospitals, 1900s-2000s (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 49. Hospitals; Cemeteries; Hotels, 1900s-2000s (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 50 - 51. Hotels (2 folders), 1900s-1950s (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
    - 52. Hotels; Libraries, 1900s-1920s (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 53. Libraries; Monuments and statues, 1900s-1950s (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 54. Monuments and statues, 1900s-1910s (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 55. Monuments and statues; Municipal buildings, 1874-1960s (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - 56. Municipal buildings; Museums, 1900s-2004 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 57. Navy Yard, 1900s-2001 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 58. Navy Yard; Restaurants, 1900s-1930s (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - 59. Restaurants; Theaters, 1900s-2005 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - 60. Theaters; Sports arenas; Transportation: Elevated lines, 1900s-2000s (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - 61. Transportation: Elevated lines, surface lines, subways, 1900s-1920s; 2000s (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - 62. Transportation: Subways, trolleys, train wreck 1965, railroads, ferries, and airports, 1900s-2000s (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - 63. Transportation: Railroads, ferries, and airports; Industrial buildings; Advertisements, 1900s-2000s (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Sub-series 2: Chronological Postcards, 1873-1990; 1873-1940
    This sub-series contains postcards postmarked from Kings County (N.Y.), dating from 1873 to 1990. It primarily consists of non-picture postcards, and includes notes on Brooklyn postal history. The sub-series is arranged chronologically.
    - Chronological Postcards 1, 1873-1886 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Chronological Postcards 2 - 6 (5 folders), 1887-1914 (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
    - Chronological Postcards 7 - 9 (3 folders), 1915-1990 (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
  - Sub-series 3: Brooklyn Eagle Postcards, 1905-1907, 1996; 1905-1907
    This sub-series contains a set of postcards published by the Brooklyn Eagle from 1905 to 1907, all of which are related to Brooklyn. It is arranged by number. The sub-series includes a related clipping (1996) and a list of postcards which are missing from the collection.
    - Brooklyn Eagle Postcards, 1905-1906, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 4-6)
- Series 2: Covers, 1814-2010; 1850-1950; 11.5 Linear Feet in 22 manuscript boxes, 1 oversized manuscript box, and 1 record carton
  The series contains Kings County covers (envelopes) and related material, dating from 1814 to 2010. Although Snitzer was mainly interested in collecting covers, the letters which were housed in those envelopes were sometimes retained and are included in the series.
  The series is divided into nine sub-series, and cross-references between the sub-series are denoted via photocopies.
  The sub-series include:
  1. Advertising Covers
  2. Stamps on Covers
  3. Stampless Covers
  4. Foreign Covers
  5. Auxiliary Markings
  6. Kings County Covers and Markings
  7. Local Substations
  9. Individual Towns
  9. Covers and stamps sales index
  - Sub-series 1: Advertising Covers, 1858-2006
    The sub-series contains advertising covers (envelopes) and related material from Kings County businesses and other organizations (government, military, hospitals, civic groups, etc.), dating from 1858 to 2006. The sub-series is arranged alphabetically by topic.
    - Index, circa 2000s (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1 - 2. Advertising collars; Architects and engineers; Artists and art studios; Banks, 1883-2004 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 3 - 4. Catalog houses and department stores; Cemeteries and undertakers; Chemicals and drugs; Clothing, 1868-1942 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 5 - 6. Clothing; Coal, fuel, glass, and lumber; Contractors, 1879-1965 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - 7 - 8. Contractors; Dry goods; Farming equipment and supplies; Florist; Food, 1877-1953 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 9 - 10. Food; Furniture, carpets, and bedding, 1879-1994 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 11 - 12. Furniture, carpets, and bedding; Ham radio; Hardware, 1880-1957 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 13 - 14. Hardware; Hotels, 1888-1951 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - 15 - 16. Hotels; Housewares; Insurance and real estate, 1858-1982 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 17 - 18. Insurance and real estate; Legal, 1860-1952 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 19 -20. Legal; Medical, 1864-1991 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - 21 - 22. Metal workers; Military, 1875-1964 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - 23 - 24. Municipal, 1868-2006 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - 25 - 26. Museums, theaters, amusement parks, and fairs; Musical instruments and toys; Occupations (Salesmen, etc.), 1864-2000s (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 27 - 28. Office supplies, stationers, printers, and presses; Organizations, 1868-2000s (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - 29 - 30. Organizations, 1851-1999 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 31 - 32. Organizations; Paints and wallpapers; Politicians, 1884-2005 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - 33 - 34. Publishers; Religious, 1873-2000s (Box 17, Folder 5)
      Includes letter from World War I soldier
    - 35 - 36. Religious; Salesmen; Schools, 1859-1988 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Includes Brooklyn Collegiate and Polytechnic Institute annual examinations program, 1859-1860
    - 37 - 38. Stamp clubs and stamp dealers; Sporting goods; Storage warehouses, 1888-1961 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      Includes Brooklyn Dodgers envelope and Ty Cobb photograph
    - 39 - 40. Tobacco; Toiletries; Transportation (automobiles, carriages, railroads); Travel agents; Utilities; Miscellaneous businesses; Unidentified, 1881-1963 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Sub-series 2: Stamps on Covers, 1832-2010; 1857-1945
    The sub-series contains covers (envelopes) with Kings County postals stamps, dating from 1832 to 2010. The covers sometimes include related letters. The sub-series also contains clippings, dating from the 1990s-2000s.
    The covers were numbered by Snitzer, and the sub-series is arranged numerically by these numbers.
    - #1 - 122 (2 folders), 1832-1901; 1991-2006 (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
    - #123 - 318 (6 folders), 1870-1927; 2000s (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
      Includes folders labeled "Columbians" and "Trans - Mississippi"
    - #319 - 739 (8 folders), 1903-1943; 1968-2000s (Box 20, Folder 1-8)
      Includes photographs of a man and his dog, and a World War I letter
    - #740 - End (3 folders), 1933-2010 (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
    - Airmail, 1918-1961 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Special delivery, postage due, parcel post, etc., 1871-1973 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Improper usage, miscellaneous stamps, non-postage, 1895-2000 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      Includes Christmas cards
    - [unlabeled], 1886-2004 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Sub-series 3: Stampless Covers, 1814-1997; 1820-1855
    The sub-series contains covers (envelopes) which do not have postage stamps, dating from 1820 to 1957. Instead, the postage amount was stamped on the cover in ink. The sub-series includes many related letters, and some related clippings from the 1990s.
    The sub-series is divided into three sections:
    1. Arranged by rates (1816, 1845, 1851, and 1855)
    2. Arranged by town, alphabetically
    3. Other stampless covers (Foreign, postage due, free franks)
    - 1. Index, Brooklyn district maps, and 1816 rates, 1820-1850; 1990s (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - 2. 1816 rates, 1820-1850 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - 3. 1816 rates, 1820-1850 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - [no number] 1816 rates, 1820-1850 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - 4. 1816 and 1845 rates, 1820-1850 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - 5. 1845 rates, 1845-1855 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - 6. 1845 and 1851 rates, 1850-1855 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - 7. 1851 and 1855 rates, 1850-1855; 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - 8. Bath Beach - Flatbush, 1830-1850; 1997 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - 9. Fort Hamilton - West Brooklyn, 1830-1850 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - 10 - 11. Williamsburg (2 folders), 1830-1855 (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
    - 12. Foreign, postage due, free franks, 1814-1945 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - 13. Free franks, 1830-1957 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Sub-series 4: Foreign Covers, 1859-2006; 1900-1950
    The sub-series contains covers (envelopes) and postcards which were sent between Kings County and foreign countries, dating from 1854 to 2006. It is arranged alphabetically by nation. The sub-series contains related clippings from the 1990s. Of note are two folders of material sent to or from Giovanni and Josephine Giunta (filed under Italy), and immigration records for Luisa Gordon (filed under Hungary). Additional Giunta material is located in the Kings County Covers and Markings sub-series, in the Censored section.
    - A - B, 1893-2001 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - C - G (5 folders), 1859-2006 (Box 24, Folder 1-5)
    - G - O (6 folders), 1854-2003 (Box 25, Folder 1-6)
      Includes Luisa Gordon immigration papers (Hungary) and 2 folders of Giovanni and Josephine Giunta letters (Italy)
    - P - V (3 folders), 1856-2004 (Box 26, Folder 1-3)
  - Sub-series 5: Auxiliary Markings, 1852-2010; 1885-1950
    The sub-series contains covers (envelopes) which contain auxiliary markings, dating from 1852 to 2010. It is arranged alpabetically by marking (registered, returned, etc.). Of note is a World War II letter from a father to his son, who was captured in the Pacific. It includes correspondence between Snitzer and Senator Charles Schumer's office regarding the letter.
    - A - F (3 folders), 1879-2007 (Box 26, Folder 4-6)
    - F - R (6 folders), 1852-2007 (Box 27, Folder 1-6)
    - R - Miscellaneous (5 folders), 1880-2010 (Box 28, Folder 1-5)
  - Sub-series 6: Kings County Covers and Markings, 1844-2006; 1860-1950
    The sub-series contains Kings County covers (envelopes) and related material, dating from 1844 to 2006. It is arranged alphabetically marking or cover type. It includes commemorative envelopes (Brooklyn Bridge, Battle of Brooklyn/Long Island, etc.), military envelopes (Civil War, World War II, naval vessels), valentines, and rare Brooklyn postmarks. It also includes articles related to philately.
    - A - C, 1845-2003 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - C (2 folders), 1844-2000 (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - Commemorative (3 folders), 1882-2006 (Box 29, Folder 3-5)
      Includes Battle of Brooklyn/Long Island, Brooklyn Bridge, Brooklyn centenary, and Floyd Bennett Field
    - Commemorative, 1900-1987 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      Includes Brooklyn Navy Yard
    - Damaged - Envelopes, 1861-2003 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Envelopes, 1888-1985 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Envelopes - First Day Covers, 1864-2000s (Box 30, Folder 4)
      Includes Battle of Brooklyn/Long Island and Brooklyn Bridge
    - Geometric Cancels (4 folders), 1849-1922 (Box 31, Folder 1-4)
    - I - Machine Cancels, 1846-2000s (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Machine Cancels (2 folders), 1891-1920 (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - Military Postmarks - Miniatures, 1869-2004 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Mourning Covers, 1861-1938 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - P, 1861-2000s (Box 32, Folder 5)
      Civil War and World War II envelopes
    - P, 1892-2005 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Railway Post Offices, 1889-1934 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - S, 1880s-1994 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - T - Miscellaneous, 1852-2001 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      Includes The Brooklyn Philatelist newsletter (1896) and a list of Manufacturers and Merchants of Brooklyn (early 20th century)
  - Sub-series 7: Local Substations, 1876-1997
    This sub-series contains covers (envelopes) which have been processed at postal substations in Kings County, dating from 1876 to 1997. For similar material, please see the Individual Town sub-series.
    The sub-series is divided into four sections:
    1. Full names, arranged alphabetically by the full name stamp of the substation.
    2. Alphabetics, arranged alphabetically by the initial stamp of the substation.
    3. Numerics, arranged numerically by the numbered cancel stamped on the cover.
    4. Alphanumerics, arranged alphanumerically by stamp (3A, 8B, etc.).
    - Full names: A - E, 1899-1997 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Full names: F - Y (4 folders), 1898-1996 (Box 34, Folder 1-4)
    - Alphabetic: A - L (2 folders), 1879-1946 (Box 34, Folder 5-6)
    - Alphabetic: M - Z (2 folders), 1876-1947 (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
    - Numeric: 1 - 15+ (2 folders), 1883-1997 (Box 35, Folder 3-4)
    - Alphanumeric, 1925-1971 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series 8: Individual Towns, 1831-2008; 1855-1905
    The sub-series contains covers (envelopes) sent from Kings County and related material, dating from 1831 to 2008. It also includes clippings, Brooklyn postal history, and maps of Kings County towns (photocopies). See also the Local Substations sub-series for similiar material.
    1. Alphabetical by town or neighborhood
    2. Alphabetics, arranged alphabetically by the initial stamp on the cover.
    - Bath Beach - Brighton Beach, 1886-1908; 1969-2006 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Brooklyn, 1839-1898 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Brownsville - East New York, 1853-1903; 2001-2008 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Flatbush - Flatlands, 1855-1894 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Fort Hamilton - Gravesend, 1831-1904; 1975-1997 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Greenpoint - West Brooklyn, 1854-1946; 1998 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Williamsburg, 1852-1886; 1990s (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Alphabetic, 1879-1898 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Numeric, 1883-1897 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Sub-series 9: Covers and stamps sales index, 1994-2000
    The sub-series contains index cards documenting the sales of Kings County covers (envelopes), dating from around the 1990s.
    - Covers and stamps sales index, 1994-2000 (Box 41)
- Series 3: Memorabilia, 1717-2002; 1880-1900; 1.5 Linear Feet in 2 oversized manucsript boxes and 1 record carton
  The series contains Kings County invoices, trade cards, property records, clippings (Brooklyn demographics, trolleys, and postal history), and ephemera, dating from 1853 to 2002. The series includes a 1717 deed belonging to the Van Brunt family in New Utrecht, and numerous property records relating to the Delapierre family. It also includes an index to bills and receipts found in the series.
  - [General memorabilia] (2 folders), 1853-2002 (Box 37, Folder 3-4)
  - Checks, notices, receipts, 1863-1943; 1995 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Craftsmen and skilled laborers (2 folders), 1867-1897 (Box 37, Folder 6-7)
  - Retailers (2 folders), 1862-1941 (Box 37, Folder 8-9)
  - Revenue Stamped Documents / Pictures, 1865-1872 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Services (3 folders), 1861-1955 (Box 38, Folder 2-4)
  - Wholesalers, 1873-1905 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Delapierre (real estate) (2 folders), 1866-1928 (Box 38, Folder 6-7)